Is comprehension the same whether a person reads a text onscreen or on paper?
一个人无论是在屏幕上还是在纸上阅读文本，理解程度都一样吗？
And are listening to and viewing content as effective as reading the written word when covering the same material?
而在所涉材料相同的情况下，收听和观看内容是否与阅读书面文字一样有效？
The answers to both questions are often “no”.
这两个问题的答案往往都是否定的。
The reasons relate to a variety of factors, including reduced concentration, an entertainment mindset and a tendency to multitask while consuming digital content.
其原因与多种因素有关，包括注意力下降、娱乐心态，以及在接收数字内容时一心多用的倾向。
When people read texts of several hundred words or more, learning is generally more successful when it’s on paper than onscreen.
当人们阅读几百个词或更长的文本时，纸质阅读的学习效果通常比屏幕阅读更好。
A large amount of research confirms this finding.
大量研究证实了这一发现。
The benefits of print reading particularly shine through when experimenters move from posing simple tasks — like identifying the main idea in a reading passage — to ones that require mental abstraction — such as drawing inferences from a text.
当实验者不再布置简单任务（比如找出一篇阅读文章的主旨），而是转向布置需要抽象思维的任务（比如从文本中作出推断）时，纸质阅读的优势就格外明显。
The differences between print and digital reading results are partly related to paper’s physical properties.
纸质阅读与数字阅读在效果上的差异，部分与纸张的实体特性有关。
With paper, there is a literal laying on of hands, along with the visual geography of distinct pages.
阅读纸质材料时，人们真真切切地用手触碰着书页，而一页页界限分明的纸张还构成了一种视觉布局。
People often link their memory of what they’ve read to how far into the book it was or where it was on the page.
人们常常把对所读内容的记忆，与它在书中的前后位置或在页面上的位置联系起来。
But equally important is the mental aspect.
但同样重要的是心理层面。
Reading researchers have proposed a theory called the “shallowing hypothesis”.
阅读研究者提出了一种名为“浅层化假说”的理论。
According to this theory, people approach digital texts with a mindset suited to social media, which are often not so serious, and devote less mental effort than when they are reading print.
根据这一理论，人们对待数字文本时，抱着一种适合社交媒体的心态，而社交媒体往往不那么严肃；同时，人们投入的脑力也比阅读纸质读物时少。
Audio and video can feel more engaging than text, and so university teachers increasingly turn to these technologies — say, assigning an online talk instead of an article by the same person.
音频和视频可能让人觉得比文字更有吸引力，因此大学教师越来越多地转向这些技术——比如，布置某人的在线讲座，而不是此人写的文章。
However, psychologists have demonstrated that when adults read news stories, they remember more of the content than if they listen to or view identical pieces.
然而，心理学家已经证明，成年人阅读新闻报道时记住的内容，比收听或观看内容完全相同的报道时更多。
Digital texts, audio and video all have educational roles, especially when providing resources not available in print.
数字文本、音频和视频都有其教育作用，尤其是在提供纸质版中没有的资源时。
However, for maximizing learning where mental focus and reflection are called for, educators shouldn’t assume all media are the same, even when they contain identical words.
然而，若要在需要专注和反思的情况下最大限度地提高学习效果，教育者不应想当然地认为所有媒介都一样，即便它们包含完全相同的文字。